[
  {
    "theme": "Active - Indicative",
    "set":1,
    "segment":"Present",
    "description": "Basic Formation",
    "difficulty":"beginner",
    "content":[
      {
        "greek":"λύω",
        "dictionaryForm":"λύω",
        "translation":"to release",
        "stem":"λύ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"present",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"1st sing - pres - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"λύεις",
        "dictionaryForm":"λύω",
        "translation":"to release",
        "stem":"λύ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"present",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd sing - pres - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"λύει",
        "dictionaryForm":"λύω",
        "translation":"to release",
        "stem":"λύ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"present",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd sing - pres - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"λύομεν",
        "dictionaryForm":"λύω",
        "translation":"to release",
        "stem":"λύ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"present",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"1st plur - pres - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"λύετε",
        "dictionaryForm":"λύω",
        "translation":"to release",
        "stem":"λύ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"present",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd plur - pres - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"λύουσι(ν)",
        "dictionaryForm":"λύω",
        "translation":"to release",
        "stem":"λύ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"present",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd plur - pres - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"φέρω",
        "dictionaryForm":"φέρω",
        "translation":"to carry",
        "stem":"φέρ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"present",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"1st sing - pres - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"φέρεις",
        "dictionaryForm":"φέρω",
        "translation":"to carry",
        "stem":"φέρ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"present",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd sing - pres - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"φέρει",
        "dictionaryForm":"φέρω",
        "translation":"to carry",
        "stem":"φέρ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"present",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd sing - pres - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"φέρομεν",
        "dictionaryForm":"φέρω",
        "translation":"to carry",
        "stem":"φέρ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"present",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"1st plur - pres - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"φέρετε",
        "dictionaryForm":"φέρω",
        "translation":"to carry",
        "stem":"φέρ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"present",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd plur - pres - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"φέρουσι(ν)",
        "dictionaryForm":"φέρω",
        "translation":"to carry",
        "stem":"φέρ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"present",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd plur - pres - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"δοκῶ",
        "dictionaryForm":"δοκέω",
        "translation":"to seem, think",
        "stem":"δοκ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"present",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"1st sing - pres - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"δοκεῖς",
        "dictionaryForm":"δοκέω",
        "translation":"to seem, think",
        "stem":"δοκ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"present",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd sing - pres - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"δοκεῖ",
        "dictionaryForm":"δοκέω",
        "translation":"to seem, think",
        "stem":"δοκ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"present",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd sing - pres - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"δοκοῦμεν",
        "dictionaryForm":"δοκέω",
        "translation":"to seem, think",
        "stem":"δοκ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"present",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"1st plur - pres - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"δοκεῖτε",
        "dictionaryForm":"δοκέω",
        "translation":"to seem, think",
        "stem":"δοκ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"present",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd plur - pres - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"δοκοῦσι(ν)",
        "dictionaryForm":"δοκέω",
        "translation":"to seem, think",
        "stem":"δοκ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"present",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd plur - pres - ind - act"
        }
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "theme": "Active - Indicative",
    "set":1,
    "segment":"Present (εἰμί)",
    "description": "Formation of the irregular verb εἰμί",
    "difficulty":"beginner",
    "content":[
      {
        "greek":"εἰμί",
        "dictionaryForm":"εἰμί",
        "translation":"to be",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"present",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"1st sing - pres - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"εἶ",
        "dictionaryForm":"εἰμί",
        "translation":"to be",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"present",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd sing - pres - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐστί(ν)",
        "dictionaryForm":"εἰμί",
        "translation":"to be",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"present",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd sing - pres - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐσμέν",
        "dictionaryForm":"εἰμί",
        "translation":"to be",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"present",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"1st plur - pres - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐστέ",
        "dictionaryForm":"εἰμί",
        "translation":"to be",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"present",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd plur - pres - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"εἰσί(ν)",
        "dictionaryForm":"εἰμί",
        "translation":"to be",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"present",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd plur - pres - ind - act"
        }
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "theme": "Active - Indicative",
    "set":1,
    "segment":"Imperfect",
    "description": "Basic Formation",
    "difficulty":"beginner",
    "content":[
      {
        "greek":"ἔλυον",
        "dictionaryForm":"λύω",
        "translation":"to release",
        "stem":"λυ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"imperfect",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"1st sing - impf - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἔλυες",
        "dictionaryForm":"λύω",
        "translation":"to release",
        "stem":"λυ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"imperfect",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd sing - impf - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἔλυε(ν)",
        "dictionaryForm":"λύω",
        "translation":"to release",
        "stem":"λυ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"imperfect",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd sing - impf - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐλύομεν",
        "dictionaryForm":"λύω",
        "translation":"to release",
        "stem":"λυ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"imperfect",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"1st plur - impf - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐλύετε",
        "dictionaryForm":"λύω",
        "translation":"to release",
        "stem":"λυ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"imperfect",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd plur - impf - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἔλυον",
        "dictionaryForm":"λύω",
        "translation":"to release",
        "stem":"λυ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"imperfect",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd plur - impf - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἔφερον",
        "dictionaryForm":"φέρω",
        "translation":"to carry",
        "stem":"φερ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"imperfect",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"1st sing - impf - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἔφερες",
        "dictionaryForm":"φέρω",
        "translation":"to carry",
        "stem":"φερ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"imperfect",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd sing - impf - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἔφερεν",
        "dictionaryForm":"φέρω",
        "translation":"to carry",
        "stem":"φερ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"imperfect",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd sing - impf - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐφέρομεν",
        "dictionaryForm":"φέρω",
        "translation":"to carry",
        "stem":"φερ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"imperfect",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"1st plur - impf - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐφέρετε",
        "dictionaryForm":"φέρω",
        "translation":"to carry",
        "stem":"φερ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"imperfect",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd plur - impf - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἔφερον",
        "dictionaryForm":"φέρω",
        "translation":"to carry",
        "stem":"φερ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"imperfect",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd plur - impf - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐδόκουν",
        "dictionaryForm":"δοκέω",
        "translation":"to seem",
        "stem":"δοκ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"imperfect",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"1st sing - impf - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐδόκεις",
        "dictionaryForm":"δοκέω",
        "translation":"to seem",
        "stem":"δοκ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"imperfect",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd sing - impf - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐδόκει",
        "dictionaryForm":"δοκέω",
        "translation":"to seem",
        "stem":"δοκ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"imperfect",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd sing - impf - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐδοκοῦμεν",
        "dictionaryForm":"δοκέω",
        "translation":"to seem",
        "stem":"δοκ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"imperfect",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"1st plur - impf - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐδοκεῖτε",
        "dictionaryForm":"δοκέω",
        "translation":"to seem",
        "stem":"δοκ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"imperfect",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd plur - impf - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐδόκουν",
        "dictionaryForm":"δοκέω",
        "translation":"to seem",
        "stem":"δοκ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"imperfect",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd plur - impf - ind - act"
        }
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "theme": "Active - Indicative",
    "set":1,
    "segment":"Aorist",
    "description": "Basic Formation",
    "difficulty":"beginner",
    "content":[
      {
        "greek":"ἔλυσα",
        "dictionaryForm":"λύω",
        "translation":"to release",
        "stem":"λυ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"1st sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἔλυσας",
        "dictionaryForm":"λύω",
        "translation":"to release",
        "stem":"λυ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἔλυσε(ν)",
        "dictionaryForm":"λύω",
        "translation":"to release",
        "stem":"λυ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐλύσαμεν",
        "dictionaryForm":"λύω",
        "translation":"to release",
        "stem":"λυ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"1st plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐλύσατε",
        "dictionaryForm":"λύω",
        "translation":"to release",
        "stem":"λυ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἔλυσαν",
        "dictionaryForm":"λύω",
        "translation":"to release",
        "stem":"λυ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐπαίδευσα",
        "dictionaryForm":"παιδεύω",
        "translation":"to educate",
        "stem":"παιδευ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"1st sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐπαίδευσας",
        "dictionaryForm":"παιδεύω",
        "translation":"to educate",
        "stem":"παιδευ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐπαίδευσε(ν)",
        "dictionaryForm":"παιδεύω",
        "translation":"to educate",
        "stem":"παιδευ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐπαιδεύσαμεν",
        "dictionaryForm":"παιδεύω",
        "translation":"to educate",
        "stem":"παιδευ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"1st plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐπαιδεύσατε",
        "dictionaryForm":"παιδεύω",
        "translation":"to educate",
        "stem":"παιδευ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐπαίδευσαν",
        "dictionaryForm":"παιδεύω",
        "translation":"to educate",
        "stem":"παιδευ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "theme": "Active - Indicative",
    "set":2,
    "segment":"Aorist",
    "description": "Aorist With Contraction",
    "difficulty":"beginner",
    "contractionRule":"In the aorist, verbs with stems ending in epsilon contract by lengthening ε to η before adding the tense marker",
    "content":[
      {
        "greek":"ἐδόκησα",
        "dictionaryForm":"δοκέω",
        "translation":"to seem",
        "stem":"δοκ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"1st sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐδόκησας",
        "dictionaryForm":"δοκέω",
        "translation":"to seem",
        "stem":"δοκ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐδόκησε(ν)",
        "dictionaryForm":"δοκέω",
        "translation":"to seem",
        "stem":"δοκ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐδοκήσαμεν",
        "dictionaryForm":"δοκέω",
        "translation":"to seem",
        "stem":"δοκ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"1st plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐδοκήσατε",
        "dictionaryForm":"δοκέω",
        "translation":"to seem",
        "stem":"δοκ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐδόκησαν",
        "dictionaryForm":"δοκέω",
        "translation":"to seem",
        "stem":"δοκ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐποίησα",
        "dictionaryForm":"ποιέω",
        "translation":"to make",
        "stem":"ποιέ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"1st sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐποίησας",
        "dictionaryForm":"ποιέω",
        "translation":"to make",
        "stem":"ποιέ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐποίησε(ν)",
        "dictionaryForm":"ποιέω",
        "translation":"to make",
        "stem":"ποιέ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐποιήσαμεν",
        "dictionaryForm":"ποιέω",
        "translation":"to make",
        "stem":"ποιέ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"1st plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐποιήσατε",
        "dictionaryForm":"ποιέω",
        "translation":"to make",
        "stem":"ποιέ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐποίησαν",
        "dictionaryForm":"ποιέω",
        "translation":"to make",
        "stem":"ποιέ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐτίμησα",
        "dictionaryForm":"τιμάω",
        "translation":"to honor",
        "stem":"τιμά-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"1st sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐτίμησας",
        "dictionaryForm":"τιμάω",
        "translation":"to honor",
        "stem":"τιμά-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐτίμησε(ν)",
        "dictionaryForm":"τιμάω",
        "translation":"to honor",
        "stem":"τιμά-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐτιμήσαμεν",
        "dictionaryForm":"τιμάω",
        "translation":"to honor",
        "stem":"τιμά-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"1st plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐτιμήσατε",
        "dictionaryForm":"τιμάω",
        "translation":"to honor",
        "stem":"τιμά-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐτίμησαν",
        "dictionaryForm":"τιμάω",
        "translation":"to honor",
        "stem":"τιμά-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐδήλωσα",
        "dictionaryForm":"δηλόω",
        "translation":"to show",
        "stem":"δηλό-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"1st sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐδήλωσας",
        "dictionaryForm":"δηλόω",
        "translation":"to show",
        "stem":"δηλό-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐδήλωσε(ν)",
        "dictionaryForm":"δηλόω",
        "translation":"to show",
        "stem":"δηλό-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐδηλώσαμεν",
        "dictionaryForm":"δηλόω",
        "translation":"to show",
        "stem":"δηλό-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"1st plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐδηλώσατε",
        "dictionaryForm":"δηλόω",
        "translation":"to show",
        "stem":"δηλό-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐδήλωσαν",
        "dictionaryForm":"δηλόω",
        "translation":"to show",
        "stem":"δηλό-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "theme": "Active - Indicative",
    "set":3,
    "segment":"Aorist",
    "description": "Aorist With Consonant Stem Shift",
    "difficulty":"beginner",
    "contractionRule":"In the aorist, the sigma contracts with specific consonants from the verb stem to form stem endings in ψ or ξ (e.g. stems ending in π, β, φ, κ, γ, χ, σκ)",
    "content":[
      {
        "greek":"ἐγραψα",
        "dictionaryForm":"γράφω",
        "translation":"to write",
        "stem":"γράφ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"1st sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐγραψας",
        "dictionaryForm":"γράφω",
        "translation":"to write",
        "stem":"γράφ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐγραψε(ν)",
        "dictionaryForm":"γράφω",
        "translation":"to write",
        "stem":"γράφ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐγραψαμεν",
        "dictionaryForm":"γράφω",
        "translation":"to write",
        "stem":"γράφ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"1st plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐγραψατε",
        "dictionaryForm":"γράφω",
        "translation":"to write",
        "stem":"γράφ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐγραψαν",
        "dictionaryForm":"γράφω",
        "translation":"to write",
        "stem":"γράφ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐπεμψα",
        "dictionaryForm":"πέμπω",
        "translation":"to send",
        "stem":"πέμπ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"1st sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐπεμψας",
        "dictionaryForm":"πέμπω",
        "translation":"to send",
        "stem":"πέμπ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐπεμψε(ν)",
        "dictionaryForm":"πέμπω",
        "translation":"to send",
        "stem":"πέμπ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐπεμψαμεν",
        "dictionaryForm":"πέμπω",
        "translation":"to send",
        "stem":"πέμπ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"1st plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐπεμψατε",
        "dictionaryForm":"πέμπω",
        "translation":"to send",
        "stem":"πέμπ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐπεμψαν",
        "dictionaryForm":"πέμπω",
        "translation":"to send",
        "stem":"πέμπ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐκρυψα",
        "dictionaryForm":"κρύπτω",
        "translation":"to hide",
        "stem":"κρύπτ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"1st sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐκρυψας",
        "dictionaryForm":"κρύπτω",
        "translation":"to hide",
        "stem":"κρύπτ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐκρυψε(ν)",
        "dictionaryForm":"κρύπτω",
        "translation":"to hide",
        "stem":"κρύπτ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐκρυψαμεν",
        "dictionaryForm":"κρύπτω",
        "translation":"to hide",
        "stem":"κρύπτ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"1st plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐκρυψατε",
        "dictionaryForm":"κρύπτω",
        "translation":"to hide",
        "stem":"κρύπτ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐκρυψαν",
        "dictionaryForm":"κρύπτω",
        "translation":"to hide",
        "stem":"κρύπτ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐφυλαξα",
        "dictionaryForm":"φυλάσσω",
        "translation":"to guard",
        "stem":"φυλάσσ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"1st sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐφυλαξας",
        "dictionaryForm":"φυλάσσω",
        "translation":"to guard",
        "stem":"φυλάσσ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐφυλαξε(ν)",
        "dictionaryForm":"φυλάσσω",
        "translation":"to guard",
        "stem":"φυλάσσ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐφυλαξαμεν",
        "dictionaryForm":"φυλάσσω",
        "translation":"to guard",
        "stem":"φυλάσσ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"1st plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐφυλαξατε",
        "dictionaryForm":"φυλάσσω",
        "translation":"to guard",
        "stem":"φυλάσσ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐφυλαξαν",
        "dictionaryForm":"φυλάσσω",
        "translation":"to guard",
        "stem":"φυλάσσ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐδιωξα",
        "dictionaryForm":"διώκω",
        "translation":"to pursue",
        "stem":"διώκ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"1st sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐδιωξας",
        "dictionaryForm":"διώκω",
        "translation":"to pursue",
        "stem":"διώκ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐδιωξε(ν)",
        "dictionaryForm":"διώκω",
        "translation":"to pursue",
        "stem":"διώκ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐδιωξαμεν",
        "dictionaryForm":"διώκω",
        "translation":"to pursue",
        "stem":"διώκ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"1st plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐδιωξατε",
        "dictionaryForm":"διώκω",
        "translation":"to pursue",
        "stem":"διώκ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐδιωξαν",
        "dictionaryForm":"διώκω",
        "translation":"to pursue",
        "stem":"διώκ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐκοψα",
        "dictionaryForm":"κόπτω",
        "translation":"to cut",
        "stem":"κόπτ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"1st sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐκοψας",
        "dictionaryForm":"κόπτω",
        "translation":"to cut",
        "stem":"κόπτ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐκοψε(ν)",
        "dictionaryForm":"κόπτω",
        "translation":"to cut",
        "stem":"κόπτ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"sing",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd sing - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐκοψαμεν",
        "dictionaryForm":"κόπτω",
        "translation":"to cut",
        "stem":"κόπτ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"1st",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"1st plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐκοψατε",
        "dictionaryForm":"κόπτω",
        "translation":"to cut",
        "stem":"κόπτ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"2nd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"2nd plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek":"ἐκοψαν",
        "dictionaryForm":"κόπτω",
        "translation":"to cut",
        "stem":"κόπτ-",
        "grammarQuestion":{
          "tense":"aorist",
          "voice":"active",
          "mood":"indicative",
          "person":"3rd",
          "number":"plur",
          "correctAnswer":"3rd plur - aor - ind - act"
        }
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "theme": "Active - Participle",
    "set": 1,
    "segment": "Present Participle (Masculine)",
    "description": "Present Active Participle Forms (Masculine)",
    "difficulty": "intermediate",
    "content": [
      {
        "greek": "λύων",
        "dictionaryForm": "λύω",
        "translation": "to release",
        "stem": "λυ-",
        "grammarQuestion": {
          "tense": "present",
          "voice": "active",
          "mood": "participle",
          "person": "",
          "number": "sing",
          "option": "nom sing - pres - act - part"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek": "λύοντος",
        "dictionaryForm": "λύω",
        "translation": "to release",
        "stem": "λυ-",
        "grammarQuestion": {
          "tense": "present",
          "voice": "active",
          "mood": "participle",
          "person": "",
          "number": "sing",
          "option": "gen sing - pres - act - part"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek": "λύοντι",
        "dictionaryForm": "λύω",
        "translation": "to release",
        "stem": "λυ-",
        "grammarQuestion": {
          "tense": "present",
          "voice": "active",
          "mood": "participle",
          "person": "",
          "number": "sing",
          "option": "dat sing - pres - act - part"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek": "λύοντα",
        "dictionaryForm": "λύω",
        "translation": "to release",
        "stem": "λυ-",
        "grammarQuestion": {
          "tense": "present",
          "voice": "active",
          "mood": "participle",
          "person": "",
          "number": "sing",
          "option": "acc sing - pres - act - part"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek": "λύοντες",
        "dictionaryForm": "λύω",
        "translation": "to release",
        "stem": "λυ-",
        "grammarQuestion": {
          "tense": "present",
          "voice": "active",
          "mood": "participle",
          "person": "",
          "number": "plur",
          "option": "nom plur - pres - act - part"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek": "λυόντων",
        "dictionaryForm": "λύω",
        "translation": "to release",
        "stem": "λυ-",
        "grammarQuestion": {
          "tense": "present",
          "voice": "active",
          "mood": "participle",
          "person": "",
          "number": "plur",
          "option": "gen plur - pres - act - part"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek": "λύουσι(ν)",
        "dictionaryForm": "λύω",
        "translation": "to release",
        "stem": "λυ-",
        "grammarQuestion": {
          "tense": "present",
          "voice": "active",
          "mood": "participle",
          "person": "",
          "number": "plur",
          "option": "dat plur - pres - act - part"
        }
      },
      {
        "greek": "λύοντας",
        "dictionaryForm": "λύω",
        "translation": "to release",
        "stem": "λυ-",
        "grammarQuestion": {
          "tense": "present",
          "voice": "active",
          "mood": "participle",
          "person": "",
          "number": "plur",
          "option": "acc plur - pres - act - part"
        }
      }
    ]
  }
]